Guide to the Herbert Humphrey Collection ARS.0106
Archive of Recorded Sound
Herbert Humphrey Collection
1960-1962
ARS.0106
Humphrey, Herbert
3 boxes: 43 7" open reel tapes
Archive of Recorded Sound
The Herbert Humphrey Collection consists of 43 open reel tapes, the majority of which bear copies of commercially-released jazz and popular music. However, at least thirteen reels are of unusual broadcast material, including a series of San Francisco performances by jazz musicians Earl Hines and Teddy Wilson, biographical programs on various musicians on radio station KFRC, and an interview with Louis Armstrong.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Scope and Contents
The Herbert Humphrey Collection consists of 43 open reel tapes, the majority of which bear copies of commercially-released jazz and popular music. However, at least thirteen reels have been identified as unusual broadcast material, including a series of San Francisco performances by jazz musicians Earl Hines and Teddy Wilson, biographical programs on various musicians on radio station KFRC, and an undated interview with Louis Armstrong by journalist Phil Elwood. Elwood appears to have further connections with this collection; several tapes suggest they were recorded by Humphrey, who was an Oakland resident, from Elwood's radio program on KPFA (from various notes in the listing: "Phil forgot to announce piece"; "Between 3rd and 4th piece, nostalgia with Phil Elwood at Hambone Kelly's" on Lu Watters Tape 37). A full listing of contents is available in the Archive.
Arrangement
Reels were arranged and numbered prior to accession. Box 1 contains #2-16 (Tape #1 is missing). Box 2 contains #17-32. Box 3 contains #33-37 as well as seven unnumbered tapes identified as "Live at the Fairmont" from Bill Bullard, which are all in fact copies of commercial albums.
- 1. Unique recordings
  - Earl Hines, Black Sheep Cafe
    Scope and Contents
    Live broadcasts of Hines performing with a sextet. Line-up is as follows: Earl Hines, piano; Dick Smith, trumpet; Pops Foster, bass; Darnell Howard, clarinet; Jimmy Archey, trombone; Earl Watkins, drums.
    Hines, Earl, 1903-1983
    - Tape 16. Earl Hines at The Black Sheep Cafe, 1961-07-06 (Audio 1)
    - Tape 17. Earl Hines at The Black Sheep Cafe, 1961-04-20 (Audio 2)
    - Tape 17. Earl Hines at The Black Sheep Cafe, 1961-05-25 (Audio 2)
    - Tape 17. Earl Hines at The Black Sheep Cafe, 1961-06-08 (Audio 2)
    - Tape 17. Earl Hines at The Black Sheep Cafe, 1961-06-15 (Audio 2)
    - Tape 17. Earl Hines at The Black Sheep Cafe, 1961-06-22 (Audio 2)
    - Tape 17. Earl Hines at The Black Sheep Cafe, 1961-06-29 (Audio 2)
    - Tape 21. Earl Hines at The Black Sheep Cafe, 1961-07-13 (Audio 2)
    - Tape 21. Earl Hines at The Black Sheep Cafe, 1961-07-27 (Audio 2)
  - KFRC biographies
    - Tape 24. The Benny Goodman Story (special 2-hour program aired on KFRC), 1962-04 (Audio 2)
    - Tape 27. The Fred Astaire Story (special 2-hour program aired on KFRC), 1962-06 (Audio 2)
    - Tape 28. The Peggy Lee Story (special 1 1/2-hour program aired on KFRC), 1962-11-11 (Audio 2)
  - Tape 12. Teddy Wilson Trio at The Blackhawk, 1960-09-25; 1.0 7" open reel tape(s) (Audio 1)
    Wilson, Teddy, 1912-1986
  - Tape 32. Phil Elwood Louis Armstrong interview (Audio 2)
    Armstrong, Louis, 1901-1971
- 2. Dubs (Audio 1, Audio 2, Audio 3)
  Dubbed copies of commercial recordings on 78, 45 and LP.